Parth Patel



What led me to futureproof was the excitement I got from fixing bugs and discovering how learning programming using online resources never felt like a chore for me. I only want to carry on further on this path and hopefully extend my expertise into machine learning. I also am extremely interested in sports, namely football, cricket, and ultimate frisbee.

SUMMARY

I attained a MSc in Forensic Anthropology and BSc (Hons) in Forensic Science from Bournemouth University, and I am currently training as a Full Stack Developer with future proof. At university, I gained interests in programming when I was exposed to basic Python for data manipulation and since then I have used internet resources to explore this passion further.

I have experience working in retail and as an intern in software development, both of which enabled me to gain problem solving skills and the ability to think outside the box.

I am now looking forward to upskilling myself with every opportunity available and exposing myself to as many new experiences as possible to improve myself.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Futureproof | Software Engineer | March 2020 - present

GitHub: www.github.com/partyzl

- 13-week bootcamp covering the main areas of web development, including JavaScript, HTML/CSS, Databases, and Python.
- Recently completed a 1-week group project using JS to create a journal entry app, using Jest to test.

QA | Software Developer in Test Internship | Oct 2020 - Jan 2021

- Using Agile Methodologies to work on projects and improve my skills in Java, web development, and testing with Junit and Mockito.
- Built my own API that could connect to front end built with HTML and Bootstrap and gained strong OO knowledge and understanding of software development processes and tools while using SonarQube to ensure high code quality.

EDUCATION

Bournemouth University | September 2014 - September 2018

MSc Forensic Anthropology (Pass)

BSc Forensic Science (2:2)

San Benito High School | August 2009 - May 2013

3.83 GPA

TECHNICAL SKILLS

HTML/CSS/Bootstrap Java SQL

JavaScript Jest/Junit/Mockito